ZIJIAN JIANG

416-877-4271 | zijianjiang@outlook.com | Toronto, ON

SUMMARY

Data Analyst and Data Engineer with broad base of experience in Database Management System, Data Cleansing and Data Visualization. Computer-savvy GIS professional with technical expertise in data pipeline design via AWS, Azure could platforms and resolving data problems in BI & AI Projects. Demonstrated strong skill in integrated analyses and visualizing geospatial data

CORE COMPETENCY

- ✓ GIS Application & Analysis
- ✓ CRM, Marketing & Transportation
- ✓ Image Processing
- ✓ Process & Workflow Automation
- ✓ Data Science Predictive Analysis
- ✓ Data Visualization & DB management
- ✓ AWS, Azure Cloud
- ✓ Data pipeline & Cleansing

OULIFICATION

- Data Science: 3D Modelling, Data Modelling, Statistic Modelling
- Data Integration: python (3 yrs), pyspark (1 yrs), SQL (2 yrs), R (2 yrs), Shell scripts (1 years)
- Cloud: AWS S3, Databricks, Azure data lake, Azure Data Factory
- Databases: MS SQL Server 2014, Azure SQL DB, MySQL, Linux, GIT
- Data visualization: Power BI (1 yr), Tableau (3 months), R, python (2 yrs), Excel, VBA(2 yrs)

EXPERIENCE

Data Analyst Trainee | EDPYPF Services Inc.

11/2021 to 01/2021

- Developed AWS S3 data pipeline for security trading summary report using python framework
- Azure ETL pipeline development in Databricks using pyspark, python and SQL
- Power BI dashboard design for CRM campaign efficiency improvement using RFM model.

Graduate Research Assistant | Data Intelligence Lab | Waterloo, ON

09/2020 to 01/2021

- Developed Ontario COVID 19 Tracker Dashboard, 2019 Global Epidemic Geo Visualization
- Researched information regarding semantic remote sensing image segmentation
- Gathered, reviewed, and summarized literature from scientific journals and produced graphsand other scientific calculations using MS Excel & VBA.
- Built & maintained Waterloo Building Database (WBD) via python & SQL, edited and created approximately 60 GB of high-resolution remote sensing image database using ArcGIS Pro

GIS Analyst Intern | Beijing Attraction Visual Tech CO. LTD

05/2017 to 08/2017

- Assisted in preparation of Traffic Staging & Conceptual Plans using Esri, ArcGIS
- Worked with geospatial professionals to optimize advertising placement of city subway network
- Assist with compiling reports and submissions of field work documentation

EDUCATION

Master of Environmental Studies: Geography (Human), University of Waterloo

09/2021

- Milestones: Achieved 90% on Master's Research Paper.
- Member of Lab Assistant at Geospatial Sensing and Data Intelligence Lab

Bachelor of Environmental Studies, Minor in Computer Science, University of Waterloo

08/2020

- Milestones: Workplace Hazardous Materials Information System
- Completed: GIS, Remote Sensing, Algorithm & Data structure, Data Analyses